["Flower Ring" by Shino Shimoji
and Aya Suzaki plays]
[whimsical music]
[crowd chattering]
- [Hiraku] Today we're
all enjoying
another peaceful morning.
The Great Tree Village has
become quite lively lately.
[Hiraku groans]
My day starts once the sun
has completely risen
each morning.
That's when I wake up.
[Hiraku sighs]
- [Lu] Good morning.
- Huh?
Hey, good morning.
Are you feeling all right?
- Geez, you ask me that
every time you see me.
- Oh, I didn't realize,
but I'm sure things
are tough for you.
Once we found out
that Lu was pregnant,
the entire village went
into a joyous uproar.
- So that's how come I haven't
been able to transform.
- [Hiraku] Is that how it works?
She was the most calm
out of everyone.
- You don't need to worry
so much about me, Hiraku.
I'm sure everything
will be fine.
- [sighs] You sure?
- Yeah, I'm going to go check
on the medicinal herb garden.
- [Hiraku] Mm-hmm, are you
fine by yourself?
- [Lu] You are doing it again.
- [Hiraku] Ah, sorry.
[Lu giggles]
Now back to my morning schedule.
According to Anne and the maids,
it's my job to keep an eye on
things around the house.
- Hello, good morning.
- Hey, morning.
By the way, there's a reason
I don't wake up too early
in the morning.
Anne and the other maids
all insist
on waking up
earlier than I do.
I sleep later
for their sakes.
I'm definitely not being lazy.
When I see her in the morning,
she lets me know if she
has anything to report.
- [Anne] Last night,
the wine slime
snuck into the
food storage area,
and drank an entire
barrel of wine.
- [Hiraku] Was that
the one we left out
to keep the wine slime
from the rest?
- [Anne] Yes, I'm not sure
if we should celebrate
our plan working,
or if we should
be lamenting the fact
that we let it
sneak in at all.
- [Hiraku] Let's just say
it went according to plan.
Once I make my rounds
around the house,
it's time for breakfast.
We can't fit everyone in
the dining hall at once,
so we split breakfast
into three groups.
- For today's main
breakfast menu,
we have a soup of daikon radish,
spinach, and cabbage,
and smoked killer rabbit
seared to perfection.
- Wow. Sounds delicious.
It looks great... hmm, Flora?
- One microorganism,
two microorganisms.
- [Hiraku] Have you
not been sleeping?
- I haven't made any
progress on the miso.
- [Hiraku] This is about
20% of the way there.
- [screams] It's because
you say stuff like that.
I'm sure I just need
more of this stuff.
- [Hiraku] I apologize, I
implore you, get some sleep.
The second breakfast group
is the maids.
Then the third group is
whoever didn't make it in time
for the first or second groups.
Sometimes Hakuren
doesn't even make it
in time for the third group.
[Hakuren snoring]
- I'm here to make a report.
- [Hiraku] Did something happen?
- [Granmaria] Yesterday, a
group of three killer rabbits
attempted to infiltrate
the village.
Kuro and the dogs
eliminated them.
- [Hiraku] I see, those rabbits
never learn their lesson.
- Well, we're able to
use them as food,
so we should be thankful
they act the way they do.
- [Hiraku] Good point.
You know?
- [Granmaria] Hmm?
- Even though Granmaria
and the other angels
always seem so composed
and proper,
they all enter lazy mode
when they're off duty
and on their own time.
They can't really do any chores,
so Anne and the maids
prepare their food,
while they rely on Daga
and the other lizardmen
to do their laundry
and other cleaning.
Well, they do make up for it
with how hard they work
to keep the village safe.
I'm glad we have them here.
- [Granmaria] Hmm?
- Hey, good morning.
Once I've eaten, it's time to
move on to working the fields.
Huh, these things again?
None of the normal garden
pests I'm familiar with
exist in this world,
but instead we have these
weird little black things
that live on the plants
and eat their leaves.
Fortunately, Zabuton's kids
or Kuro and the other dogs
can spot them for us.
As of now, they've yet
to cause any real damage.
And the way I deal with them is-
[pests screaming]
Using the almighty farming
tool as a watering can.
Apparently it has the power
to eliminate garden pests.
The fields that we've
been slowly expanding
have become quite large in size.
Checking on all of them
is pretty tough now.
But seeing all the matured
crops fills me with joy,
and with a sense of satisfaction
for all the work we've done
[sighs].
While I'm working on my chores,
lunch time comes around.
I eat the lunch that
Anne and the maids
prepare in between
my work. [moaning]
[girls giggling]
Apparently having lunch
in this world
is very out of the ordinary.
- A meal in the afternoon?
But we just had a big meal
this morning.
- I felt the very same way
when I first came here.
- [Hiraku] Lunch aside,
Lea and the high elves
were nervous about
even eating breakfast.
- [Lea] Is it okay
if we eat today too?
Will our food reserves
hold out at this rate?
- [Hiraku] According to them,
sometimes they went without
eating even a single meal.
- You mean we get to eat food
every single day?
We're definitely going to
get kicked out
of this village one day,
aren't we?
- [Hiraku] How did she
reach that conclusion?
I want to make sure that
none of them have to worry
about food as long as
they're living here.
- Excuse me, Mayor.
- [Hiraku] Hmm?
- The cows gave birth
to their calves.
I would like to increase
their allotted feed.
- Yeah, do that.
- Hiraku, our crop storage room
is going to be full soon.
- Shall we bring Michael here,
and talk about selling
more of what we produce?
- Yeah, talk to Flowrem
on quantity.
[Hiraku groans]
After lunchtime ends,
it's back to work.
Having more people around
has helped with the
farm work a lot, hmm?
[dog whimpering]
But tilling new fields
or planting new crops
is something I handle myself
with the almighty farming tool.
[Hiraku grunts]
[mysterious music]
Up until now, I've only been
growing stuff we could eat,
but I think adding a
little color to our village
is good for making things
feel civilized.
Outside of the farm work I do,
the villagers ask me to build
all sorts of little
things for them.
Thanks to the
almighty farming tool,
I can make things for them
even though I have no
experience in construction.
I thank God for
these blessings.
I also like to occasionally
join everyone
for their battle training.
[swords thudding]
But Anne and the maids
strongly advised
we hold regular training
just in case
anything should happen.
Oh well, getting some
more exercise
is good for everyone's health.
[woman grunts loudly]
Huh?
[women panting]
- Okay, let's keep going!
If we keep eating the way
we currently do
in this well-stocked village,
one day we'll no longer
be able to fit
into our sacred maid uniforms!
I think mine's already starting
to become a tighter fit!
Let's go!
- Maybe I need some
more exercise.
[mysterious music]
[Hiraku groans]
[Hiraku grunting]
[sword thudding]
I'm already at my limit.
Huh?
I bet I'd be better
with that one!
Can I try it out?
- Sure, that's fine by me.
[Hiraku grunting]
[air whooshing]
- This is harder than I thought.
[daggers clang]
[Hiraku yelps]
I guess I'm really not suited
to use normal weapons.
But I still have this spear!
[Hiraku grunts]
[air whooshes]
[Ya yelps]
[crowd howls]
- That was so amazing!
How did you do that?
- [Hiraku] I'm not exactly
sure when I can use this.
Once the sun starts to set,
I wrap up the work
I was doing and head home.
Oh, I've never seen
this dish before.
- [giggles] This is a new
menu item we're trying out.
It's simmered killer rabbit
served with a sweet
buttery honey sauce.
Please give it a try, sir.
- How confident?
- About 20%.
- That's pretty low.
- Super sweet!
- I'd like you to
only present dishes
that you have at least
50% confidence in.
- I can not do that.
We can not afford to waste
any of our food.
- [Hiraku] Good point.
[Hiraku grunts]
I did my best to enjoy the meal.
[Hiraku chuckles]
At dinner time, a lot more
people gather around the table.
We report anything that
we want everyone to hear.
- Mayor, Princess Yuri
has sent a letter to you.
- Huh, wonder why?
Let's see,
"I'd like to eat the apples
from your village again.
"Also, I'd like a dress."
What is this?
- She really liked the clothes
that Zabuton made for her
while she was here,
and was wondering if she
could have more made.
- I see.
- [Flowrem] I apologize.
I'll tell her to stop making
so many requests of us.
- Well, I'm sure Zabuton will
be happy to make something.
[water trickling]
Once I've rested a bit after
dinner, it's bath time.
I pretty much have the men's
bathhouse all to myself.
I couldn't really relax when
we only had one bathhouse.
I'm really glad I forced them
to build a men's bathhouse.
This is paradise.
After I get out of the bath,
it's time to relax,
or at least... I wish it was.
This is usually where
I start to feel uneasy.
- He's about to enter his house.
- Right, I've got
eyes on him here.
- He's headed
straight for his bedroom.
- Understood.
[Hiraku sighs]
- Why is it that I can still
feel their eyes on me
even though I'm inside my room?
Ah, someone help me!
[doors thud]
- [Leef] Our cover is blown!
- [Lea] Everyone, retreat!
- [Hiraku] I'm sure they're
just keeping watch
because they want to
keep me safe.
That's what I tell myself.
[Hiraku groans]
Oh well, even with stuff
like that happening,
I couldn't be happier with
my everyday life here.
God, thank you once again
for giving me a
second chance at life.
I'll do my best again tomorrow.
Oh yeah, I need to have
those hidden doors
sealed up tomorrow too.
Farming Life...
- [Lu] ...In Another...
- [Hiraku] ...World.
Whether it's day or night
here in the village,
Donovan and the dwarves
are always hard at work
making alcohol.
When it comes to dwarves,
I used to imagine them
being merry,
and getting drunk all the time.
[dwarves laughing]
- There's no way we could
possibly produce good alcohol
if we were drunk while working.
- Indeed, you're right.
Even the man in charge of
watching the fire would-
- The man in charge of the fire
drinking on the job?
Out of the question!
That could cause a fire!
- Indeed, you're right.
As you can see, they take
their job very seriously.
[Hiraku groans]
- Do you think this is okay?
- Nope, this one here
is no good.
- [Hiraku] Huh?
- It's lost it's flavor.
This is bad booze that does
nothing but burn your throat.
- So, are you gonna
throw it away?
- Nope, we've still got
uses for this.
We'll distill it some more,
and then cut it with a variety
of different fruit juices.
All right, back to
the drawing board.
Let's rethink how
we're distilling it.
- [Hiraku] I have nothing
but respect
for the passion with which
they make alcohol.
- [Donovan] Hey, Mayor!
- [Hiraku] Hmm?
- Could you increase the amount
of grapes we're harvesting?
I need three times
the current harvest.
- [Hiraku] Oh, okay,
I'll see what I can do.
Increase the harvest
three times?
Three times, huh?
Well, everyone here
really loves their wine.
- [Sena] Mayor!
- Hmm?
[Sena panting]
What is it?
- Hmm, there's this
strange man that showed up.
- A strange man?
[dramatic music]
It's a strange man?
How did he even make it
this far in the first place?
He got by Granmaria and
Zabuton without them noticing?
- Oh, is that the Progenitor?
- Lulucy!
[Hiraku grunts]
[Lu giggles]
- Ah, the Progenitor?
- [Flora] It's been
a long time, Progenitor.
- You look quite well, Flora.
- [Flora] I am.
- When I first heard that
Lulucy was with child,
I was positive there must have
been some sort of mistake.
It looks like I was wrong.
- Yes, I'm quite
surprised myself.
- That's right,
we vampires usually tend
to continue our bloodline
by forming new bloodpacts,
though rarely [chuckles].
But children are
a lovely treasure.
You must take care of yours.
- Yes, I will, thank you.
- What do you mean
he's the Progenitor?
- Ah, to put it simply,
I guess you could say
that he would be
the equivalent of
a grandfather.
- Grandfather?
- That's right,
I'm 4,000 years old now.
- 4,000?
- Well I sorta forget
the exact number.
- [Hiraku] I can't see him
as anything
other than a
regular young guy.
- The trick to a long life
is to occasionally
erase your memories.
- Your memories?
- [Vargryfe] I make sure to
keep the important stuff,
like my name and
the clan I belong to,
then I make everything else
go poof and forget about it.
- It goes poof and gone?
Isn't that kind of scary?
- It was a bit scary
the first time,
but I got used to it
after that.
It's been about 200 years
since last I did it,
so I still feel pretty young
and vibrant now.
- I didn't know vampires
had that sort of ability.
- [Vargryfe] We don't,
I use magic for that.
- Magic sounds really
useful to have.
- Oh, by the way,
I'm sorry I entered the village
without saying hello.
I had planned to just have a
look around and then leave,
but I was drawn in
by a certain presence.
- Presence?
- That great statue
below the big tree!
It is simply wonderful!
It's truly a splendid likeness
of the great creator!
Before I knew it, I was bowing.
- Oh, that's what you meant.
If you know his likeness,
does that mean
you've met God before?
- [Vargryfe] Yes, just once,
when I was born.
He told me to do my best,
even though I'd have
an abnormal body.
- And by abnormal body
he meant vampire?
- I believe so.
And thanks to that advice,
I feel like I've faced
a lot of hardships
and been saved
a number of times.
But I can't be sure since
I've erased my memories!
Oh well, I get the feeling
that I've done my best!
[Vargryfe laughs nervously]
[Flora sighs]
- Okay.
- However, I do remember
the great creator.
It's just I'm afraid I can't
remember his exact appearance.
Was he an old man?
Or maybe a young man?
What color were his eyes?
What color was his hair?
I've tried numerous times
to create a likeness of him,
but I've never created
anything as real as that.
I'm sure living nearby
a masterpiece like that,
means that every single day
of your life is amazing!
It must be so nice!
I'm so jealous! Wow!
- He wants it, right?
- [Lu] Mm-hmm.
- Amazing, oh, so beautiful!
- Um, about that statue.
It belongs to the village,
so I don't think I can
offer it to you.
[head thuds]
- I knew it.
I get it, but it's too bad!
Mm, too bad!
I am reading the room
right, yeah?
- [Hiraku] Uh-huh.
[Flora and Lu whimpering]
- Too bad.
- If you'd like-
[Vargryfe groans]
I could make you a new one.
I'm not a sculptor,
so I'm not sure if you'll
like what I make or not.
- You mean it?
I'd love that so much!
I am so happy.
Thank you, Mayor!
[all chuckle]
- [Hiraku] How do you like it?
[dramatic music]
- I think he likes it.
- I think you're correct.
- Sorry for the sudden request.
How much should I
pay you for it?
- Nothing, I can't take
money for this.
God isn't something that you're
supposed to profit off of.
- I understand,
then I'll have to think about
something else
I can do as thanks.
Lu, make sure you give birth
to a healthy baby.
- Yes.
- [Vargryfe] Good health
to you too, Flora.
- And you as well, Progenitor.
- [chuckles] And Mayor,
thank you for everything.
I'm grateful for this statue,
and for what you've done for Lu.
Keep taking care of her, okay?
- Yes.
[Vargryfe humming]
I was surprised at first,
but he's easygoing.
- He sure is.
- And to think, he's such an
incredibly high ranking person.
- Hmm, is he really
that important?
- [Temple Master] Oh, my lord!
[intense organ music]
Welcome back.
- It's been a while.
How many years?
- I believe it's been
50 years since last time.
As you can see, I've lived long
enough to become an old man.
- [Vargryfe] So you're in charge
of the temple now?
- [Temple Master] Yes,
it's going on 30 years.
- [Vargryfe] Well, you've always
been a devout believer.
You're the man for the job.
- [Temple Master]
Thank you very much.
- [Vargryfe]
Has anything changed?
- Not a thing.
Everything is as it
always was, My Lord.
- I see, I'm rather glad
to hear that,
but there's going to be a
big change starting today.
- What might you mean
by that, My Lord?
- I want to enshrine this
statue here in this temple.
- [Temple Master] You do,
what kind of statue is that?
- You'll just have to
wait and see.
I want you to put it in
the very best spot.
- Hmm, well, if that's the case,
then we would have to move out
the statue of the creator
that was crafted by the
master sculptor, Toorook.
But we can't move
the most beloved statue
in this temple from
its resting place.
- Yeah, of course we can.
- Yes, sir.
Oh...
This is such a
majestic work of art.
It must have been made by
quite a famous sculptor.
We must be sure that everyone
properly honors their name.
- I think it would be
better if we didn't.
He doesn't strike me as the type
to appreciate stuff like that.
Besides, I'd rather not disturb
the peaceful life he's built.
- Hmm, that is most unfortunate.
- Although, I think it's fine
if we were to quietly
support him.
- Right.
- Let all the other temples
know immediately.
Tell them to be
respectful of him,
as well as respectful of
The Great Tree Village.
- [Temple Master] Right away.
[Hiraku sneezes]
- Are you okay, Mayor?
- Yeah, yeah, that just
caught me off guard.
It's been a long time
since I've sneezed.
[light piano music]
Huh?
The Progenitor sent us
a magnificent piano.
I refused to take
payment for the statue,
so this was a gift
for Lu's pregnancy.
He's really considerate
for someone so important.
We talked for a while about
where we would put it.
- [Daga] [groans] There we go.
- [Hiraku] We decided on
the village's dining hall.
Thanks guys, good work.
- [Daga] Good work, everyone.
- The piano that was gifted.
- Is it the kind you would find
only in a large temple?
- Yeah, that's the kind of piano
that only gets used
for big ceremonies.
- Hey, guys, you think
we can play it?
- This is a once,
no, more like a never in a
lifetime chance to play one.
- [Roaju] [sighs] That means
if we can play this piano now,
we'll be able to brag about this
for the rest of our lives!
[all sighing]
- You can go first, Roaju.
- Huh?
- I'm fine with
playing later too.
[Roaju yelps]
[all sigh]
This thing is way too scary
for us to even try playing!
- My hands are sweating so much!
- If we break it, that will be
the end of our short lives!
- Huh, you want another piano?
- For, for us to practice on.
- Please, Mayor?
We don't mind if it's old and
raggedy and beat up badly.
- Actually, an old piano
would be for the best.
- Can't you play
the one we have?
- [Girls] No, we can't do it!
- What, huh, why are you crying?
We talked to Michael,
and had him procure
a practice piano for us.
Hmm...
I don't really know
anything about these,
but the one we got from the
Progenitor seems a lot fancier.
Now I feel bad that he sent us
something so nice.
[upbeat piano music]
The pianos were a hit.
Everyone wanted to play.
The only ones who
could already play
were Flowrem and the girls
from the Demonic Kingdom,
but everyone else seems to enjoy
practicing to get better.
[upbeat piano music]
[intense piano music]
[groans]
I just wish they'd stop
playing at night.
[intense piano music]
["Feel the winds"
by Yui Hizuki plays]
[rustic music playing]